(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T22:32:54.648287",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Attention / ご来場のお客様へ
Attention / To All Attendees
二次販売グッズ
Second Round Merchandise Sales
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon...
常闇トワ JACK!
Tokoyami Towa JACK!
[Tokoyami Towa JACK!]
あ、こっちこっち！
Ah, over here!
今日二人じゃないんっすね。
So you guys aren't alone today.
え？二人。
Huh? It is just the two of us.
さっきの、ここで会った人たち。
They're just the people we met here earlier.
え？
Wait, what?
心で...
In my heart...
Joyで行こうぜ！
Let's go with Joy!
JOYSOUND X1
常闇トワ 2nd Live 『SHINIER』
[Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live: SHINIER]
常闇トワ 2nd Live 『SHINIER』 有明アリーナ 2025.10.29
[Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live 'SHINIER' at Ariake Arena, October 29, 2025]
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
[Attention: Notice to Visitors]
二次販売グッズ
[Second Round Merchandise]
常闇トワ 2nd Live * SHINier *
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live 'SHINier'
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will start shortly.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
二次販売グッズ / 応援セット
[Merchandise] Secondary Sales / Support Set
二次販売グッズ / Tシャツ・タオル・バッグ・缶バッジ
[Merchandise] T-shirt, Towel, Bag, Button Badge
二次販売グッズ / ポーチ・ハット・アクリルブロック
[Merchandise] Pouch, Bucket Hat, Acrylic Block
二次販売グッズ / ブレスレットライト
[Merchandise] Bracelet Light
常闇トワ 2nd Live * SHINier *
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live 'SHINier'
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will start shortly.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention to Visitors
二次販売グッズ：応援セット、Tシャツ、フェイスタオル
Second Batch of Merchandise: Support Set, T-Shirt, Face Towel
リバーシブルトートバッグ、缶バッジ
Reversible Tote Bag, Can Badge
ポーチ、バケットハット、タオルハンカチ、アクリルブロック
Pouch, Bucket Hat, Towel Handkerchief, Acrylic Block
ブレスレットライト
Bracelet Light
常闇トワ 2nd Live 「SHINIER」
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live "SHINIER"
ご来場のお客様へ
Attention to all visitors
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援OKです
Please be aware of flashing lights. / Cheering loudly is OK.
二次販売グッズ / 応援セット
Second Round Merchandise Sales / Support Set
Tシャツ / フェイスタオル / トートバッグ / 缶バッジ
T-Shirt / Face Towel / Tote Bag / Button Badges
ポーチ / バケットハット / タオルハンカチ / アクリルブロック
Pouch / Bucket Hat / Towel Handkerchief / Acrylic Block
ブレスレットライト
Bracelet Light
常闇トワ 2nd Live SHINier
有明アリーナ 2025.10.29
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live SHINier
Ariake Arena - October 29, 2025
Attention
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援OKです
Attention
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering out loud is OK.
二次販売グッズ
応援セット
Secondary Sales Merchandise
Support Set
二次販売グッズ
SHINierライト、Tシャツ、フェイスタオル、トートバッグ、缶バッジ
Secondary Sales Merchandise
SHINier Light, T-shirt, Face Towel, Tote Bag, Badge
二次販売グッズ
ポーチ、バケットハット、タオルハンカチ、アクリルブロック
Secondary Sales Merchandise
Pouch, Bucket Hat, Towel Handkerchief, Acrylic Block
二次販売グッズ
ブレスレットライト
Secondary Sales Merchandise
Bracelet Light
見える？ この目の涙
Can you see the tears in my eyes...
命の色に滲んでいる
...blurring into the color of life?
何を残して与えた？
What did I leave behind and give?
問いかけて潰れて
I ask, and I break down.
青と赤と白 交ざる
Blue, red, and white mix,
この世の中で叫んでいる
and I'm shouting in this world.
何を求めて歩いた？
What was I searching for as I walked?
追いかけて疲れて
Chasing after it, I grew tired.
どのくらい異常？
How abnormal is it?
壊れているの？
Am I broken?
壊れているよ
I am broken.
それでも息を...
Even so, I...
...したい したい
...want to breathe, I want to breathe.
君に見えてるの？
Can you see it?
夢のように最後の
Like a dream, the last...
言葉も詰まるよ
...words are choking up, too.
error
遠い日のこと
Those distant days...
淡い光が空に溢れている
...a faint light is overflowing in the sky.
何を選んで並べた？
What did I choose and line up?
涙色重ねて
Layering the tear colors.
浮かぶその身体
That floating body...
意識の中 溶けて滲んでしまう
...melts and blurs away within consciousness.
何を見てきて比べた？
What did I look at and compare?
悲しくて忘れて
In sadness, I forgot.
どのくらい異常？
How abnormal is it?
歪んでいるの？
Is it distorted?
歪んでいるよ
It is distorted.
それでも息を...
Even so, I...
...したい したい
...want to breathe, I want to breathe.
夢を見ているの？
Am I dreaming?
想う君に最後の
Thinking of you, the last...
言葉も詰まるよ
...words are choking up, too.
error
与えることも失うことも
Whether giving, losing,
忘れることもできないの
or even forgetting, I cannot do any of it.
溢れ出すこのエラーをして笑う僕がまた
With this error overflowing, I laugh at myself...
いる
...once again.
壊しているの
Am I breaking it?
壊して知るの
Do I only learn by breaking it?
それでも涙痛い痛い
Yet still, these tears hurt so much.
君に届いたの
Did they reach you?
歌う声に最後の
Even if I align my final words...
言葉並べても
...within my singing voice...
重なる色に滲んで
...they bleed into overlapping colors,
壊れていくの
and begin to break.
壊れているの
They are already broken.
それでも息をしたいしたい
Yet still, I want to breathe so badly.
君に見えてたの
Were you able to see it?
夢のように最後の
Like a dream, even...
言葉も詰まるよ
...my final words get caught.
エラー
Error.
乾いた 虚しさと
A dry emptiness,
小さな この空を 抱いた
and I embraced this tiny sky.
彼方の色 手を伸ばすほどに
The colors in the distance, the more I reach out...
遠くなる
...the further away they become.
僕たちは何度も
Time and time again,
何度も
over and over...
問いかけて
...we keep on questioning.
灯火は 迷わず 照らすかな
I wonder if the light will guide us without doubt.
まだ世界は
With the world still...
目を閉じたまま
...keeping its eyes closed,
やがて消えていくの
it will eventually fade away.
静かな 暗闇と
A quiet darkness,
確かな 感覚を
and a definitive sensation.
君の吐き出す息が
If the breath you exhale...
灰色にこぼれ落ちたら
...spills out in shades of grey,
全て試されているみたいで
it feels as though everything is being tested.
抱えていたいもの
The things I wish to hold onto,
何度も失って
losing them over and over again.
この日々が夢であるなら
If these days are but a dream,
まだ僕らは 目を閉じたまま
then with our eyes still closed,
やがて消えて
we will eventually fade...
崩れていく
...and crumble away.
やめてよ
Please stop it,
揺れる感情を
these swaying emotions.
僕たちは
Within our mistakes,
過ちの中で何度も試されて
we are tested time and time again,
まだ正義や愛と呼ぶけど
though we still call it justice or love.
この世界は目を閉じたまま
With this world still keeping its eyes closed,
やがて消えて
it will eventually fade...
崩れていく
...and crumble away.
Oh...
...何も見えなくて
...nothing in sight,
まだ私は 息を止めていた
I was still holding my breath.
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私は...
It's okay, even if it's far, I want to make it come true...
超えるこの広い世界 想いも 抱きしめていたいのに
...this wide world, even though I want to embrace my feelings.
夢のキャンバスに 映し続ける意味は
On the canvas of dreams, the meaning of continuing to project them...
この胸に 輝いている Slowly
...is shining inside my heart... slowly.
変わることに 意味などないけど
There's no meaning in changing, but...
古い冷たい...
...the old, cold...
かけがえのないもの失うの
...will I lose what is irreplaceable?
そして夜はその冷たさを 溶かして手を伸ばした
And so, the night melted away that coldness, and I reached out my hand.
もういいよ 遠くても 届けたい 私は
It's okay, even if it's far, I want to deliver it...
受け止めてゆく 涙も 抱きしめていたいのに
...I will accept it, even though I want to embrace my tears too.
夢のキャンバスに 心込めるのは
Putting my heart into the canvas of dreams...
この空に 描き出していく Slowly
...is to paint it onto this sky... slowly.
そして夜はその冷たさを 溶かして手を伸ばした
And so, the night melted away that coldness, and I reached out my hand.
もういいの 遠くても 叶えたい 私の
It's okay, even if it's far, I want to make it come true...
超え出す世界 想いも 言葉で包んだ
...my emerging world, I wrapped even my thoughts in words.
夢のキャンバスに 彩りを足していく
Adding color to the canvas of dreams...
この胸に 今輝いて
...shining inside my heart now.
強くなくてもいい
It's okay not to be strong,
壊れかけてもいい
it's okay even if I'm breaking down.
この心は 永遠に羽ばたいて
This heart will flap its wings forever...
響くように
...so that it resonates,
塗り替えていく パレット
I'll paint over it with my palette.
みんなー！
Everyone!
常闇トワ、トワ様です！
I'm Tokoyami Towa, Towa-sama!
あ、トワ様って出してくれてるんだ。あはは、イェーイ！
Ah, you're holding up 'Towa-sama' signs! Ahaha, yay!
常闇トワ 1st... セカンドライブ「Scream」いよいよ始まりました！
Tokoyami Towa's 1st... 2nd Solo Live 'Scream' has finally begun!
えー、ちょっとびっくりすると思うんですけど、最初に「-ERROR」を歌わせていただきました！
Well, I think you might be a bit surprised, but at the very beginning, I sang '-ERROR'!
びっくりした人ー？
Who was surprised?
そうだよね、そうだよね。びっくりしますよね。
I thought so, I thought so. It's surprising, right?
で、その後に「Twilight」と「Palette」を歌わせていただきました！
And after that, I sang 'Twilight' and 'Palette'!
えー、やっぱね、「-ERROR」を持ってきた理由なんですけれども、
So, regarding the reason why I chose to start with '-ERROR'...
やっぱりね、あの「-ERROR」を聞いて、常闇トワのことを知ってくれたみたいな人が、やっぱり多いと思うんだよね。
...I think there are probably a lot of people who learned about Tokoyami Towa after hearing '-ERROR'.
そうだよね？
Right?
そう、多いからなんかちょっとエモいの持ってこようかなーみたいな感じで、もうそんな感じで、ぽろっと、さらっと、決めちゃいました！
Yeah, since there are many, I thought, 'Maybe I should bring something emotional,' and just like that, I casually decided on it!
なんか、結構最初のほうに、こう、しっとりする曲を持ってきたのは結構挑戦的だったのかなと思うんですけども、
I think starting off with quiet, emotional songs was quite a challenge, but...
どうでした？
...how was it?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え、みんな、Tシャツ着てくれてるやん！
Oh, everyone is wearing the T-shirt!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ペンライトはね、あの、凶器にもなりかねないので、気をつけてください。
And please be careful with the penlights, as they can sometimes turn into weapons.
いや、可愛いけど！可愛いのに！
I mean, they are cute! Even though they are cute!
の声がちょっとあの、トガりすぎたっていう...
...my voice was a bit too edgy...
まあ、そう、そう、それもありますけども...
Well, yeah, yeah, there's that too...
あ、思い出として残しておいてください。
Please keep it as a memory.
はい！そしてね、今回...
Yes! And so, this time...
えー、ライブなんですけども、
Well, about this live concert...
セカンドアルバムが、えー『シン』というアルバムになっていまして...
My second album is called "SHIN"...
ま、ライブもね、その『シン』に沿って、えー『シャイナ』という風に...
And so the live concert, following "SHIN", is titled "SHINA"...
付けさせていただいてます。いただいてます。
...which is what we've named it.
あの、歌はいいけど、喋りが下手っていう...
Like, "She sings well, but she's bad at talking"...
致命的に下手なんだけど大丈夫そうか？
I'm fatally bad at it, but is it okay?
あ、ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you very much, thank you very much.
えー、このね、『シャイナ』はね、えー『光る』とか『輝く』っていう意味があるので、
And this "SHINA", you see, has the meaning of "to light up" or "to shine"...
今日のね、ライブは、来てくれてるみんなの心を、
So in today's live, everyone who came here, your hearts...
輝かせるようなライブにしていきたいと思います！
...I want to make this a live concert that makes them shine!
えー、セカンドアルバムの楽曲もいっぱいあるので、
Well, we have lots of songs from the second album...
楽しみにしていてください。
So please look forward to them.
えー、ありがとう。
Well, thank you.
アルバムも買ってくれましたか？
Did you buy the album too?
ありがとう。嬉しいです。なんか今日も、ちょっとライブ前に、あの、エゴサをしてたんですけども...
Thank you. I'm so happy. Actually, today, just before the live, I was ego-searching...
あの、いっぱい「現地でも買いました」みたいな、ポスカ...ポストカード？
And I saw a lot of posts like, "I bought it at the venue too," getting the postcard...
「ゲットしました！」みたいな感じで、
...like, "I got it!"
ツイートしてるのを見て、あ、ポストしてるのを見て、すごい嬉しかったです。
Seeing you tweet—ah, seeing you post that, I was really happy.
まだ慣れないんだよね、うん。
I'm still not used to saying "post" instead of "tweet", yeah.
えー、そして、
And also,
今日なんですけども、ファーストと一緒で、生バンドでやっております！
For today, just like the first one, we are performing with a live band!
いえーい！かっこよかったでしょ？もう最初だけじゃないから、これからずっとかっこいいのを演奏してくれます。
Yay! It was cool, right? It's not just the beginning, they'll keep performing cool stuff for us all the way.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Please show them your support.
はい！えー、今日しか、なんと！今日しか聴けない、ライブアレンジが...
Yes! And, what's more, there are live arrangements you can only hear today...
...あるので、楽しんで盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです！
...so I hope you enjoy and get hyped up!
はい！そして、
Yes! And...
今日は現地だけじゃなくて、配信もしております！
today is not just on-site, we are also streaming!
なんと、ここら辺に手を振ると、
If I wave my hand around here,
可愛いトワちゃんが、あの、インターネットに...
...the cute Towa-chan is... on the internet...
あ、ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you very much, thank you very much.
はい、はい、あんまりそんな、あの、あの、言われて慣れて、慣れてないもんで、はい。
Yes, yes, I'm not really used to being called cute, yes.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
はい、えー、なんかいろんなとこにアピールしながらやっていこうかなと思っております。
Yes, so I'm planning to perform while appealing to everyone everywhere.
えー、そして今回の、
And so, this time's...
えー、ハッシュタグなんですけれども、ライブの感想、ハッシュタグ...
...hashtag for your thoughts on the concert...
シャープ「常闇トワセカンド」でたくさんポストしてください！
Please post a lot with #常闇トワセカンド!
スクリーンショットOKということなので、いっぱい、
Screenshots are okay, so please take lots of...
あの、ちょっといい、あの、盛れてる感じのでお願いいたします、スクリーンショットして、あの、投稿する場合は。
...please make sure it's a good-looking one when you screenshot and post them.
はい、お願いいたします。
Yes, please.
そして、なんと、
And, surprisingly...
これいつもの流れだから分かっちゃうかもしれないけど、
Since this is the usual flow, you might already know this, but...
そうなんです、えー、YouTubeとTikTokでご覧の方は、えー、ここまでとなっております。
That's right, those watching on YouTube and TikTok, this is the end of the free section.
すいません。
I'm sorry.
「えー！」お前らは「えー！」じゃないだろ。
"Eh?!" You guys shouldn't say "Eh?!"
いるだろ、何が「えー！」なんだよ。何に対しての「えー！」なんだよ。
You're already here! Why are you going "Eh?!" What is that even for?
ね、あの、配信の、見てくれてる人の「えー！」を、
Ah, you mean the "Eh?!" from the streaming viewers...
代弁してくれたってことね？
...you're speaking on their behalf?
そうだよね、そうだよね、そうだよね。
Right, right, that's it.
はい、なのでね、えー、まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは、
So, everyone who still wants to get hyped together...
概要欄から配信サイトをチェックして、購入してくださいね！
...please check the streaming site in the description box and purchase your ticket!
はーい。
Okay~
ということで、
With that said,
次の曲、
the next song...
いこうかなと思うんですけども、
I think we should move on to, but...
えー、まずちょっと、アンケートをとりたいと思います。
First, I'd like to do a quick poll.
えー、本日、えー、東京から来たよって方！
First, who here came from Tokyo today?
あ、半分ぐらいかな？半分ぐらい？
Ah, about half of you? About half?
えー、じゃあ、東京じゃないとこから来た人！
Okay, then, those who came from outside of Tokyo!
めちゃくちゃ多いよ！めちゃありがとやん！
There are so many of you! Thank you so much!
えー、じゃあ、
Well, then...
じゃあ、北海道から来た人！
Then, those who came from Hokkaido!
いるやん！まじかよ、ありがとう。
There are people! Seriously? Thank you.
じゃあ、沖縄から来たって人！
Then, those who came from Okinawa!
あ、いるいるいるいる！ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Ah, there are! Thank you, thank you, thank you!
はい、じゃあ、ちょっとあの、もっと拡大していいですか？
Yes, then, can I expand the scope a bit more?
えー、日本じゃないとこから来た人！
Well, those who came from outside of Japan!
おいおい、めちゃくちゃいるじゃないか。
Whoa, there are so many of you!
おお、すごい、すごい、ありがとう。
Wow, amazing, amazing. Thank you.
えー、じゃあ、さらにめちゃくちゃ絞って、
Okay, then, narrowing it down even further...
えー、じゃ、飛行機を...
Well, then, who took a plane...
おお、12時間以上乗ってきた人！
Whoa, anyone who traveled over 12 hours?
えっ
Eh?
いるやん！
There really are some!
え、すご
Wow, amazing.
ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます
Thank you so much, thank you so much.
ということで、なんか「わー」って今言えました？
So, were you guys able to yell "Woohoo!" just now?
まだでも足りないか
But that's still not enough, is it?
じゃ、トワ、掛け声しちゃおうかな
Then maybe Towa should lead a chant.
盛り上がれますかー？！
Are you ready to get hyped?!
お、結構最初なのに声出てるやん！
Oh, your voices are coming out great even though it's just the start!
なんか、何回かやろうかなって思ったけど、結構声出てたけど
I thought about doing it a few times, but you guys were already pretty loud.
じゃ、もう一回言っていいか？じゃあ
Well, can we do it one more time then?
盛り上がれますかーーー？！
Are you ready to get hyped?!
うおお、じゃあ！
Woooo! Alright then!
次の曲いくぞーーー！「Reap」！
Let's move on to the next song! "Reap"!
いくぞ、有明ーーー！
Here we go, Ariake!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free broadcast has ended. Thank you for watching!
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching!